亲爱的 有一部休·格兰特...
Hey, honey, Hugh Grant has a--
算我一个
I'm in.
好的 艾丽克斯11点有大提琴课
Okay, well, Alex has a cello lesson at 11:00...
中午要参加象棋课
and Junior Congress at noon.
她不是还要上一辈子的光棍课吗
Doesn't she also have no boys at forever?
你还是关心一下自己的饮食失调问题吧
Don't you have an eating disorder you need to attend to?
不管怎么说 可以看4点或6:20的场
Yeah, anyway, uh, we could see the 4:00 or the 6:20.
实际上 那两场我都去不了
Oh, actually, that's no good.
我要和丹妮丝去喝点东西
I'm meeting my friend Denise for a drink.
丹妮丝 我认识吗
Denise? Do I know Denise?
是啊 就是我前女友
Yeah. You know, my old girlfriend.
老天 想到你和一个女人在一起就恶心
Oh, my God. Gross. I can't even picture you with a woman.
-谢谢 -你还有前女友
- Thank you. - You had a girlfriend before Mom?
而且是两个
Try two.
我之前一直过得很快活
Trust me. I had plenty of fun in my time.
直到遇见了你妈
And then I met your mom.
谢谢"恭维"
And thank you.
她应该是四处奔波
So I guess she travels
为某个化妆品公司做推销
around selling makeup for a cosmetics company.
会在城里待一周
She's in town for a week.
你是说 她是个挨家挨户的推销员
You mean she's like a door-to-door salesman?
换成是你 就是个呆家呆户的推销员
If you were doing it, they'd call it a dork-to-dork salesman.
一记漂亮的突袭
My boy strikes like a rattlesnake!
是吗 那 那你就是
Oh, yeah? W-Well, you-
好了 电影明天再去看
Wow. All right, well, we can see the movie tomorrow.
跟我走 该去上课了
Come on. It's time for your lesson.
是第二堂课 她刚刚可是被我教育了一课
You mean her second lesson, because she just got schooled.
我今天是怎么了
What's wrong with me today?
算了 宝贝 今天你的水平发挥不出来
Shake it off, champ. It's not your day.
-早上好 小家伙 -是吗
- Ay, good morning, papi. -Is it?
还在为试镜结果难过吗
Ay, you're still sad because of that audition.
那角色是我的 我生来就该演特维
That part was mine. I was born to play Tevye.
他们竟然让罗德·杰克逊来演
Instead they give it to Rod Jackson?
他哪里懂什么叫受苦受难
What does he know from suffering?
-情况如何 -略有起色
- How are we doing? - A little better.
不过这问题得用冰激凌解决
But we're gonna go and throw ice cream at the problem.
要是冰激凌都没用 就试试这个
Well, if that doesn't work, this should do the trick.
"大难不死 人自更强"
"What doesn't kill us makes us stronger."
把这个挂在你房间
We can hang this in your room.
每天早晨看一眼 用心去体会
You can see it every morning, start to internalize it.
以后什么都打不倒你
Pretty soon nothing will keep you down.
但那话不对
But it's not true.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
很多大难只会让人更脆弱
Lots of stuff that doesn't kill you makes you weaker.
我朋友的爷爷只是患了心脏病
My friend's grandfather had a heart attack.
现在连喘气都要靠一台机器支撑
Now he needs a machine to breathe.
我见过他 就在超市里
I've seen him- at the supermarket.
走到哪都得推着一台
Now he needs to drive one of those little, like-
好了 你继续悲观教育吧
That's right. Be negative.
那幅画确实不怎么样 杰
It's just not a good poster, Jay.
你的打击只会让我变得更坚强
You're only making me stronger.
-喂鸭子的面包带了吗 -带了
- Did you pack the bread for the ducks? - Yes.
不要全麦的 鸭子不吃
Not the whole-wheat kind. The ducks don't like that.
米奇尔 鸭子是不会介意的
They're ducks, Mitchell. They don't care.
我们都觉得
We both believe that
动物在莉莉成长过程中是不可或缺的
animals should play a big part in Lily's life.
我在农场上长大 接触过很多动物
Having grown up on a farm, I was surrounded by them.
它们更像是我的兄弟姐妹
They were more like brothers
而不仅仅是牲畜家禽
and sisters than just, you know, livestock.
多美味的兄弟姐妹
Delicious brothers and sisters.
生在农场 它们深知以后的命运
Life on a farm- they know what they're getting into.
才怪
Eesh.
等等
Oh, wait.
-公司打来的 -别接
- Oh, it's the office. -Don't answer it.
我必须得接
I have to.
每周六都来这一套 别接了
It's like this every Saturday. Just ignore it.
也许这次不是呢 喂
Well, maybe it's not that this time. Hello?
看吧
Yeah.
真不错
That's nice.
我靠..小壳 你还好吗 哥们
Holy- Shel? You all right, buddy?
该死
Oh, hell.
一共4只小鸭子呢 米奇尔
Oh, there's four of 'em, Mitchell.
它们在亲莉莉
They're giving her little duck kisses.
她笑得很开心 真遗憾你看不到
Oh, she's laughing. I can't believe you're missing this.
那又怎样 小卡 我错过的还少吗
Well, why not, Cam? I've missed everything else.
她第一次翻身 我在凤凰城
She rolled over when I was in Phoenix.
她学会爬行时 我却在法庭上
She started scooting when I was in court.
告诉他们你不去加班 你做的够多的了
Well, just tell 'em you're not coming in. You do enough for 'em.
关于这一点 你知道 我也知道
Well, you know that. I know that. You know?
只有我那个混蛋老板不知道
The only one who doesn't know that is my sucky boss.
他是有史以来最混蛋的混蛋
He's the suckiest suck of all time.
他个可怜的贱人
He's a miserable son of a bitch who...
好像听到了我刚才说的话
may have heard everything I just said.
-嗨 亲爱的 -嗨
- Hi, honey. -Hey.
什么时候去见你的女性朋友
When are you getting together with your gal pal?
事实上 我正在等消息呢
Actually, I was just checking on that.
她还没给我发站内信
She's supposed to send me a message.
原来你加了她的Facebook
Oh, you're Facebook friends.
当然 她只是447个好友之一
Sure am. She's one of my 447 friends.
大家都对我想入"菲菲"呢
Everybody wants a slice.
你们恢复联系有多久了
How long have you two been in touch with each other?
她差不多一年前联系到的我
Uh, she tracked me down about a year ago.
怎么了 你什么意思
What? What's- What's that sound?
没什么
Mmm. Nothing.
站内信终于来了
Oh. Here she is right now.
"七点半 梦境餐厅见"
"How about we meet at Le Reve at 7:30?"
你们的约会真够"单纯"的
That sounds innocent enough- I mean-
和前女友在一家适合幽会的法国餐厅喝酒
drinks with an ex-girlfriend at an intimate French restaurant.
亲爱的 你说的话正是我期盼从你口中听到的
Honey, you're doing that thing when you say what I want you to say
但你的语气好刻薄
but your tone seems mean.
让我猜猜啊 丹妮丝还没结婚
Let me guess. Denise isn't married.
最近才离的 这有什么问题
Recently divorced. What's the big deal?
得了 菲尔 别太傻太天真
Come on, Phil. You can't be that naive.
说真的 网上那些奔四的女人
Seriously, women in their 30s on the Internet are like-
个个都是忍者
they're like ninjas.
换上黑色外套
They get into their little black outfits
暗地里当第三者插足别人的婚姻
and try and sneak their way into your marriage.
丹妮丝不是那种人
That's not Denise.
你看 这都是她给我发的站内信
Here. Read some of her messages.
-你看完就知道你想多了 -好吧
- You're gonna feel silly. - Okay.
"嗨 菲尔 最近怎么样啊"
"Hey, Phil. How's it going?"
你别乱加性感的勾引声音
You can't add the sexy voice.
"嗨 菲尔 过得怎么样"
"Hi, Phil. How's it going?"
"得知你脖子不疼了 我很高兴"
"So glad to hear your neck is better."
-你真吃醋了 -没有
- Are you seriously jealous? - No,
我一点都没吃醋
I am not jealous at all.
只是比你更懂女人而已
I just happen to know women better than you do,
那女人绝对对你存有非分之想
and that woman wants a slice.
好吧 为了证明你的想法是错的
Okay. Just to prove how wrong you are,
我打算邀她来家里喝酒
I'm gonna invite her over here for drinks.
我无所谓 但愿她不介意
Fine with me. Just hope it's fine with Denise.
"哎呀菲尔 我整颗心都在梦境餐厅"
"Gee, Phil, I really had my heart set on Le Reve."
你故意刻薄的声音可不会让我生气
That voice doesn't bother me.
反而让我喜欢
Kind of like it!
他有什么反常的举动吗
Has he been acting weird around you?
没有 我一上午都躲着他
No, no. I've been avoiding him all morning.
所以说你其实根本不知道他听没听见
So you don't even know if he heard you.
所以叫你来帮忙
That's why we're doing this.
你到哪了 午餐时间只有半个小时
And where are you? I only have a half hour for lunch.
你好 帅哥
Hello, handsome.
早上就是在这里碰见他的
So this is where it happened.
关掉手机
Just turn off the phone,
摇下车窗 试试能不能听见我说话
roll down the window and we'll see if you can hear me.
请绕行 我们要重现骂人的过程
Go around! We're re-creating a faux pas!
谢谢
Thank you.
好了 能听见我说话吗
Okay. Can you hear me now?
可以 但听不太清
Yeah, but just barely.
你之前骂的时候这么小声吗
Is this how loud you were talking?
可能比这个音量大一点
It might have been a little bit louder.
当时路上都是车 几乎得用喊的
There was traffic. I almost had to shout.
- 几乎得什么 -用喊的
- You almost had to what? - Shout.
-大点声 -用喊的
- Little bit louder now. - Shout.
-再大点声 -用喊的
- Little bit louder now. - Shout!
别闹了 小卡 我的工作要保不住了
Really, Cam? My job is at stake here, and-
开什么玩笑 显然你一开始就听得清
Oh, who are we kidding? You can obviously hear me.
我彻底完了
I am so screwed.
曼尼 曼尼 过来一下
Manny? Manny, come here a second, pal.
-什么事 -有个坏消息要告诉你
- Huh? - I got some bad news, buddy.
什么坏消息
What is it?
我很难以启齿
Well, there's no easy way to say this.
小壳·斯坦龟死了
Shel Turtlestein is dead.
什么 怎么死的
What? How?
当时我正在看报纸
I was down here reading the paper,
只听楼上你的房间一阵骚乱的声音
and I heard this commotion up in your room.
出 出于本能反应 我跑上楼
So- so naturally, I go running up there.
看见一只脏兮兮的浣熊已经破窗而入
And this mangy raccoon had busted through your screen.
它肯定是跳到了小壳的鱼缸旁边
He must have scampered up to where Shel was.
因为我进去的时候 那个坏家伙
By the time I walked in, he had-
正抓着小壳的脖子使劲甩
the little bastard had him by the neck and shaking him.
碎石被甩得到处都是
Gravel was flying everywhere.
它看见我一点都不怕
He didn't even flinch.
还得意地盯着我看 然后一下子就溜了
He just stared at me with that smug look and then bolted.
我真后悔没有早点上来
If only I'd have got here earlier.
我能看看小壳的尸体吗
May I see the body?
宝贝 你真的要看吗
Baby, are you sure that's a good idea?
再痛苦我也必须面对
It's something I have to do.
-确实是它 -对不起 哥们
- That's him. - Sorry, pal.
可是完全说不通呀
It just doesn't make any sense.
是啊 好龟不长命
Yep. Only the good die young.
老师说 浣熊只在夜间行动
But in school, we learn raccoons are nocturnal.
白天都在睡觉
They sleep during the day.
当然 这一只可能是半夜起来找零食的
They sure do, and this one must've got up for a midnight snack.
我们人也有类似的经历嘛
You know, we've all done that.
-应该是吧 -是啊
- I guess so. -Yeah.
现在都能说得通了
It all adds up.
我现在无法待在这个房间 太多回忆了
I don't think I can be in here right now. Too many memories.
他会没事的
He'll be okay.
-你撒谎 -什么
- You lie. - What?
在哥伦比亚 骗局我见一个识破一个
I'm Colombian. I know a fake crime scene when I see one.
我当时想把那幅画钉在墙上
I was hanging up the new poster
结果它掉下来砸在小壳身上 纯属意外
and it fell on top of him. It was an accident.
去跟他说实话
You have to tell him.
不行 我有经验
No. I've been through this before.
米奇尔九岁的时候 他让我照看他的鸟
When Mitchell was nine, I was supposed to take care of his bird.
结果它飞了出去 撞上了一台电扇
It got out and flew into a fan.
那场面就像血花四溅的枕头大战
It was like a bloody pillow fight.
老天 你到底杀过多少只宠物
My God. How many pets have you killed?
就这两只
Just the two.
我不小心害死了那只鸟 是大错特错
I took the heat on the bird. It was a big mistake.
直到今天 米奇尔看我的眼神
To this day, Mitchell looks at me,
都好像在说
I see him thinking,
"芙莱莎·米奈丽就是被这个人杀死的"
"That's the guy who killed Fliza Minnelli."
要是曼尼发现了 你又要怎么办
And what if he finds out? Then what?
到时候你不仅是宠物杀手 还是个骗子
You'll be the guy that killed his pet and lied to him.
他不会发现的 我已经掩盖好自己的"行迹"了
He's not gonna find out because I covered my tracks.
好吧
Okay.
芙莱莎·米奈丽
Fliza Minnelli?
我当时怎么就没发现他是同性恋呢
How did I not know that kid was gay?
嗨 卢克
Hey, Luke.
今天可是你的大日子
Big day for you, huh?
为什么
Why?
-你终于可以见到你的亲妈了 -什么
- Because you will get to meet your real mom. - What?
本来大家说好 等你21岁再告诉你
We all made a pact we'd deny it until you turned 21.
但是爸爸的前女友就是为这事来的
But that's the real reason Dad's old girlfriend's coming over.
她才是你亲妈
She's your mom,
要是她喜欢你 你就得跟她生活了
and if she likes you, you'll go live with her.
我才不是被领养的 我要去问妈妈
I'm not adopted. I'm asking Mom.
你是说邓菲太太吗 她不会跟你说实话的
You mean Mrs. Dunphy? She's not going to tell you the truth.
我不是
I-I'm not-
我知道
I know.
就因为他说你是呆家呆户的推销员吗
Just 'cause he called you a dork-to-dork salesman?
姐全力回击
The empire shakes back.
浣熊爪有5个指头
Raccoons have five toes.
什么
What's that?
我不想来烦你
I don't mean to bother you.
但我很疑惑
It's just confusing.
我房间里浣熊的两只脚印都只有4个指头
The footprints in my room only have four toes.
我知道怎么回事
You know, I bet I know what happened.
它肯定是在一场打斗中失去了两个指头
I'll bet he lost those toes in a fight.
那家伙看起来像是经过了几场打斗
And that guy looked like he'd been in a brawl or two.
-刚好一只爪失去一个指头 -有可能
- One toe from each foot? - Maybe.
曼尼 只有一件事
You know, Manny, I think the only thing...
可以让你不再问这样的问题
that's gonna get you to stop asking all these questions...
就是 一个永久性的告别
is for you to have a little closure.
什么意思
What do you mean?
给小壳举办一场小型追悼会吧
Well,I'd like to throw a little memorial for Shel.
那对我们大家都好
It'll be good for all of us.
那样就可以把悲痛发泄出来
That way we get our grief out,
之后谁都不要再提这件事 永远不提
and then we never have to talk about this ever, ever again.
嗨 当心脚下
Hi. Oh, careful. There's a thing.
见到你真高兴
Yeah. Good to see you.
-嗨 -嗨 我是克莱尔
- Hi! Oh, my God. - Hi. I'm Claire.
你就是 嗨
You must be- Oh. Yeah. Hi.
-丹妮丝 -是的
- Denise. - Well- Okay.
你本人比菲尔上传的照片还要漂亮
You're even prettier than the pictures that Phil's always posting.
-只有几张 -是吗
- Just a couple. - Oh?
瞎说 每周都有
Shut up. Every week.
他喜欢炫耀你的照片
He loves showing you off.
我男友喜欢你在阿卡普尔科照的那几张
And my boyfriend likes your Acapulco pictures,
喜欢得我都有点吃醋了
probably a little too much.
替我谢谢你男友
Well, thank your boyfriend for me.
快请进
Come on in, please.
我给你带来一瓶祛皱紧致霜
Oh, I brought you, um, some lifting intensifier.
我知道你用不上 不过这是限量版
Not that you need it. It's a limited edition,
-谢谢 谢谢 -不客气
- Thank you. Thank you. - Never mind.
丹妮丝 给你介绍我的孩子
Oh, Denise, I think you might know these people.
-这是海莉 -嗨
- Uh, that's Haley - Hi.
-艾丽克斯和 -卢克
- Alex and- - Luke.
他的卷发和我小时候的一模一样
I had curly hair just like that when I was little.
那又怎样 说明不了什么
So? That doesn't mean anything.
大家都过来 请坐
Why don't we, uh, come on in, have a seat. Please.
爸爸上高中时候是什么样子
So what was my dad like in high school?
他的霹雳舞无人超越
Only the most amazing break-dancer ever.
-不可能 -别刺激我 你看 你看
- No way. - Oh, don't fire it up. What? What?
他柜子里有一个大匣子和一块硬纸板
He had a boom box and a piece of cardboard in his locker.
-你那个舞叫什么名字 -O型区
- And what was your dance name? - O-Zone.
我开车送他去搜星节目试镜
I drove him to his Star Search audition.
顺便提一下 试镜就是走个形式
Which is totally political, by the way.
O型区
O-Zone.
太搞笑了 我以后就叫你这个
That is dead-ass funny. I'm so calling you that.
谢谢
Thank you.
你太走运了
Wow. You really lucked out.
美丽娇妻 豪华住房
You have a beautiful wife, a gorgeous house.
还有一群孩子 我都想把卢克带回家去
And those kids- I could take Luke home with me.
不用跟我客气
Well, be my guest.
真的 赶紧把他带走吧
Seriously, you go right ahead.
不行 我喜欢这个家
No! I like it here!
艾丽克斯 宝贝 看看你弟弟怎么了
Alex, honey, will you go find out what's wrong with your brother?
遵命
Okay.
如果可以的话 我想去一下
You know, um, if it's okay, I think I'm just gonna use the, um-
当然可以 走廊尽头就是
Oh, yeah. Of course. Down the hall.
-就在左手边 很容易找到 -谢谢
- Left-hand side. You can't miss it. - Thanks.
-我承认她人很棒 -是吗
- Okay, she's fantastic. -Yes?
是 我好愧疚
Yes. I feel awful.
什么时候起 我变得这么刻薄
When did I become this horribly cynical person...
把别人都往坏处想
who assumes the worst about people?
其实7年前我就发现...你才不是那种人
I first noticed it seven years- You're not.
我太笨了 请问
Such an idiot. Is it-
-我带你过去 没关系的 -谢谢
- Oh, I'll show you. Yeah, yeah, yeah. - Okay. Thanks.
我们要怎么做
So how are we gonna do this?
我以为只要给你指一下门
I thought I'd just point at the door.
-所以我只想着 -我也是这么想的
- So I was thinking - I was thinking too.
这个 是我酒店的房卡
Here... is my hotel room key.
随时欢迎你
You can come by whenever you want.
今天早上挺有意思的 是吧
That was funny this morning, huh-
红灯的时候我刚好停在你的车旁边
when I pulled up next to you at that stoplight?
有意思
Funny?
对 当时我正在和我老公打电话
Yeah. Because I was on the phone with my partner...
谈论他的上司多讨厌 他的上司
talking about how horrible his boss was- his.
然后你刚好停下 所以
And then you pull up. So-
不管怎么说 很高兴路上碰见你
Anyway, I'm glad I ran into you.
我担心他们要把开庭日期提前
I'm getting worried they're gonna move up our court date.
所以你要全力做好准备
I need you to bust ass preparing.
因为一旦周一叫我们去开庭
'Cause if they call us on Monday-
一定要现在看吗
Uh, you need to get that?
不是 没关系 只是一张
No. It's fine. It's just a...
我女儿第一次站起来的照片
picture of my daughter standing for the first time.
可以理解 确实值得庆祝
Yeah, they do that. It's a big day.
无论如何 明天你还要来加班
Anyway, I need you here tomorrow.
我知道明天是周日 但是
I know it's a Sunday, but,
你肯定会准时到的 好吗
uh, you think you can be on time, okay?
其实 明天我有事
Actually, um, I have plans tomorrow,
就不来了
uh, so I won't be here.
我打算明天待在家里
I-I have plans to stay at home
和家人一起 什么都不做 就这样
with my family and do absolutely nothing. Okay.
不过周一我还是会来上班
But I will see you on Monday.
你的意思是 这事你说了算
So, you're in charge now, is that it?
我才意识到 既然我女儿都能站起来
Well, I just figure if my daughter can stand up,
我也应该起身反抗
then so can I.
好了 最近大家加班都很辛苦
All right, look. We've all been working hard lately, okay?
但这是工作性质决定的
But that's the job.
明天不来 你就永远不用来了
So either come in tomorrow or don't bother coming back again.
好吧
Okay.
还得用一下证件
Need the, uh, I.D. to
乘电梯下楼 奔向自由
make the elevator go down to freedom...
还有咖啡 配合我的行头
and this to complete my set.
乌龟 爬行动物 宠物
Turtle, reptile, pet.
小壳·斯坦龟不仅仅是一只乌龟
Shel Turtlestein was many things.
再说下去我就要哭了
I don't think I can do this without crying.
不如我们直接跳到吃冷盘的环节吧
Maybe we should just get to the cold cuts.
我们想听完
Well, we wanna hear it.
杰 要不你去念吧
Jay, why don't you read it?
是你"送它上路"的 记得吗
You were with him at the end. Remember?
"小壳·斯坦龟不仅仅是一只乌龟"
"Shel Turtlestein was many things,"
"最重要的是 它是我的朋友"
"but above all, he was my friend."
"当菲奥娜·冈德森拒绝我的约会请求"
"When I didn't get a date with Fiona Gunderson,"
"有小壳的见证"
"Shel was there."
"当我落选特维的角色"
"When I didn't get to play the part of Tevye,"
"有小壳的见证"
"Shel was there."
"而当一只浣熊闯入我的房间"
"And when a raccoon broke into my room,"
"不幸的是 小壳也在"
"unfortunately, Shel was there.
"跟这位朋友 我说过很多话"
"I said a lot of things to my friend,"
"但最终却来不及跟它说一句再见"
"but the one thing I never got to say was good-bye."
等一下 我知道它是怎么死的了
Stop. I know what really happened.
-是吗 -我床边上有一包薯条
- You do? - I left a bag of chips near my bed.
浣熊肯定是闻到味了 是我害死了小壳
The raccoon must have smelled it. It's my fault he's dead.
对不起 小壳
Sorry, Shel.
杰 有什么话要跟曼尼说吗
Jay, you don't have anything to say to Manny?
好吧
Yeah.
曼尼
Manny.
小壳不会怪你的
Shel forgives you.
谢谢
Thank you.
丹妮丝
Oh, Denise.
这些照片太棒了 谢谢你
These pictures are amazing. Thank you.
亲爱的 你还是卷发呢
Sweetie, that perm.
确切地说是杰里卷
Technically, that's a Jheri curl.
我特喜欢照相 今天还给自己照了一张
I just love to take pictures. I took this one of myself today.
话说 我去开一瓶红酒
You know what? I'm gonna open a bottle of wine.
不要 千万不要
No. No. That's the worst idea.
别开 我没那个心情
No, no. I'm not in the mood.
我是怎么了 像个狼孩一样
What am I, raised by a pack of wolves?
嗨 别闹了
Hey. Come on now.
亲爱的
Honey.
你对丹妮丝的判断也不是一点道理没有
You weren't completely wrong about Denise.
-为什么这么说 -她想要我
- How's that? - She wants me.
-干什么 -那个 干她
- To do what? - It. Her.
我说Facebook上的女人不正经
Oh. Oh, this is because of the thing I said about Facebook...
大家都在上面约炮 所以你失望了
and everybody's hooking up, and now you're disappointed.
不是 她对着我大口咬空气 像这样
No. She bit the air right in front of me. Like that.
而且你看她塞给我一个什么
And then look what she tried to give me.
-需要我帮忙吗 -不用了
- Anything I can help with? - No.
我找不到开瓶器了
I just- I can't find my corkscrew.
-摸我 -好了 丹妮丝
- Touch me. - Okay. Denise,
肯定是有什么地方让你误会了
I think somewhere along the line you got the wrong idea.
我脑袋里充满想入"菲菲"的误会
My head is full of wrong ideas.
-你的品味真不赖 克莱尔 -谢谢
- You have such great taste, Claire. - Thank you.
菲尔当年也是很有品"味"的
I remember Phil used to have really good taste too.
-我用点洗手液 -找到了
- Let me get a little of this. - Oh, here it is.
菲尔 拿几个杯子过来
Phil, would you mind grabbing us a couple glasses?
没问题
You betcha.
-要我帮忙"抓"什么吗 -不用
- Need me to grab anything? - No!
-这样太离谱了 -我知道
- Okay, this is so wrong. - I know.
-有她在更刺激不是吗 -不是
- It's way more exciting when she's in the room, isn't it? -No.
我还留着拉拉队队长的衣服
I still have my cheerleader outfit.
我也是
So do I.
但还是不能这样 那个怎么碎了
But this still can't happen. When did that break?
-你怎么退却了 -我根本没想乱来
- Why are you wussing out? - I never wussed in.
那你在Facebook上写那些是为什么
What about all those things you wrote on Facebook?
"你还好吗 我脖子好疼"
"How was your day? My neck is so sore."
怎么大家都要把留言说的那么下流
Why do people keep adding voices to these things?
我没别的意思
I didn't mean anything.
你是说 我在这段关系上
Are you telling me that I wasted a year
浪费了一年时间
of my life on this relationship?
什么关系
What relationship?
还有多少女人被你勾引了
How many other women have you led on?
靠 我怎么知道
No, I don't know!
菲尔
Phil?
菲尔 亲爱的
Phil, honey.
记不记得 我们第一次约会的时候
Do you remember when you broke your arm
你的胳膊受伤了
when we were first dating?
记得 我在冰上摔倒了
Yeah, uh, when I slipped on the ice.
是啊 奇怪了 这张照片里
Right. That's so weird. Because in this picture,
你带着受伤的胳膊坐在丹妮丝旁边
you're sitting with Denise and you have a broken arm, so-
是 是挺奇怪
Yeah, that's- that's weird.
-你和我约会的时候和她还没断呢 -不是
- So you were still dating her when you started dating me? - No.
-菲尔 -可能是吧
- Phil? - Yeah. Maybe.
有段时间 我横跨两条船
There was a time, a little overlap...
当时 我打算和丹妮丝分手
when, uh, I was trying to break things off with Denise.
那你还带我去圣达菲
You took me to Santa Fe.
圣达菲 你当时说是带你爸爸去
Santa Fe? Phil, you told me that was your father.
我知道你们很"新疼" 但其实都是旧伤
Okay, I know the pain is fresh, but the lie is really old.
我来就是个错误 我走了
You know, this was a mistake. I'm gonna leave.
克莱尔 我要是你 就把他踢出家门
Claire, if I were you, I would kick him out.
可能他会更加感激你
Maybe he'd appreciate you
让他尝到孤身一人在酒店过夜的滋味
more after he spent a lonely night in a hotel.
在机场旁的雷迪森酒店
At the Radisson, by the airport.
-你辞职了 -感觉太棒了
- You quit? - It was amazing.
在你眼前的是一个全新的我 小卡
No, no. This is the new me, Cam.
我再也不会让别人主宰我的生活
I am not letting people run my life anymore.
我应该紧张才对 但我反而为你激动
I should be nervous, but I'm not. I'm excited for you.
没错 这太令人激动了 太激动了
Yes! It's exciting! It's exciting.
你听从了自己内心的想法 值得庆祝
Because you followed your heart, and that is worth celebrating.
小卡 我觉得自己
Cam, I just feel-
彻底解放了
so liberated.
我不会去捡起来的
And I'm not picking it up.
-我喜欢你这样 -我也是
- I like this guy. - I do too.
当然 我们以后要节俭一些
Yes, we'll have to cut back a little bit.
但这值得 不是吗
But isn't it worth it if you feel
第一次为自己而活
like you're living your life for the first time?
-太值得了 -那我们还等什么
- Totally. - What were we even waiting for?
你重操旧业 当音乐老师
You will go back to teaching music,
我休息几个月 再找一份工作
and then I'll just find something in a... few months.
在那之前 我们只管坐下来
And until then, all we need to do is just sit back...
看着我们的小千金快乐成长
and watch this little miracle here dazzle us.
-我好激动 -我也是
- I'm tingling. - I am too.
我的心似乎从没这么充实过
It's like my heart is full for the first time in forever.
老天 心跳得好快
Oh, God, it's really pounding.
我能感受到
It's like I feel the weight of
我的胸口充满了一切可能
endless possibilities just sitting on my chest-
她什么表现都没有 小卡
She is not doing anything, Cam.
你不是慌乱了吧
You're not panicking, are you?
-我当然慌乱了 -你别慌乱
- Of course I am panicking. - No. Don't panic.
你一乱 我也乱
If you panic, I panic!
我刚辞职了 小卡 老天啊
I just quit my job. Cam! My God.
米奇尔 我过惯了好日子
Mitchell, I am used to nice things.
以后要怎么办
What are we gonna do?
别慌 镇定下来
Okay. No, no. Just calm down.
我来规划一下该怎么办
This is what we're gonna do.
我要 我要用我的看家本领
I am going to- I'm gonna do what I'm trained to do.
为达目的不惜说谎
I am going to lie, grovel, debase myself
卑躬屈膝 自我贬低
until I get what I want.
我可是律师 妈的
I am a lawyer, damn it.
米奇尔
Mitchell!
不要
No.
提醒的好 忘了打领带
Oh, no, you're right. The tie.
我是说 我们一定能找到更合适你
No. We'll find something better for you,
而且对大家都好的办法
something that works for all of us.
没有备用方案的 小卡
There's no Plan "B" here, Cam.
我们要还房贷 还要养个孩子
We have a mortgage. We have- We have a child to support.
一切都会好的
Hey, it's gonna be okay.
我们肯定有办法
We're gonna figure it out.
我只希望你开心 你一定会开心的
I just want you to be happy, and you will be happy.
这才是值得庆祝的事
And that is something worth toasting.
喝那个便宜的吧
Let's just drink the cheap stuff,
那瓶贵的我们转手卖掉吧
'cause we might have to sell that bottle.
说谎太多容易失眠
It's hard to sleep in a bed of lies.
对不对 杰
Isn't it, Jay?
小孩记性很差
Kids get over these things pretty quick.
没准他现在像婴儿一样熟睡呢
He's probably sleeping like a baby right now.
他肯定是清醒着的 满心愧疚
I'm sure he's wide awake, full of guilt.
反正我要睡觉了
Well, I'm going to sleep.
妈的
Damn it!
你好 杰
Hello, Jay.
-你怎么不睡 -我在等待
- What are you doing up? - Waiting.
等什么
Waiting for what?
等真相 浣熊不是凶手 对吗
The truth. It wasn't a raccoon, was it?
好了好了 被你发现了 是我的错
Oh, all right. You got me. I killed Shel.
行了吧 对不起 我不是故意的
All right? I'm sorry. It was an accident.
你当时为什么不说实话
Why didn't you just tell me?
我不想惹你生气
Because I didn't want you to be upset with me.
我们一开始关系很僵
You and I got off to a rocky start.
最近 好不容易相处融洽了
Lately, it's been pretty good.
我害怕毁了这一切
I was afraid I'd mess all that up
所以不想让你知道是我杀死了你的宠物
if you knew that I was the one that killed your pet.
但你现在不仅杀了我的宠物
Now you're the guy who killed my pet
还编了个愚蠢的谎言
and made a stupid lie about it.
我不觉得那是个愚蠢的谎言
Well, I don't think it was stupid.
我以为挺聪明的
I thought it was pretty clever.
我只是不想重蹈覆辙
I was just trying to avoid past mistakes.
听着
Look.
我知道我现在无法弥补对你造成的伤害
I know I can't make things all better right now,
但我相信以后会的
but maybe over time.
也许吧
Maybe.
好好睡吧
Get some rest.
既然你已经坦白了 我也该坦白
Since we're confessing things,
还记得你车上的抓痕吗
you know that scratch on your car?
就是一直擦不掉的那个 记得
The one that can't be buffed out? Yeah?
你应该猜得到是怎么回事
You should probably know how it happened.
我知道是怎么回事
I know how it happened.
是浣熊干的
Raccoon did it.
-晚安 杰 -晚安 小家伙
- Good night, Jay. -Good night, kid.
我最大的成就
Best thing I ever did
就是辞了份烂工作 自己创业
was quit a miserable job and start my own business.
-谢谢老爸 -不过自己创业也不容易
- Thanks, Dad. - No, it's not gonna be easy.
所以我和歌洛莉亚来送你个东西
That's why Gloria and I wanna give you a little something
帮你渡过难关
to help you through it.
爸爸 我不能
No, Dad, I can't.
一定要给你 米奇
No. I want to, Mitch.
辞职之后 我特别想
Okay, but, I mean, as soon as I'm back on my feet, I really want to-
爸爸 不要 你
Oh. Oh, Dad. No. You-
20年前我的宠物蛇死了 你就想给我这个的
You tried to give me this 20 years ago when my pet snake died.
-是吗 -是
- I did? -Yes.
-叫扎扎·戈波娃 -这名字真可爱
- Zsa Zsa Gaboa? - Oh, that's adorable.
你当时真不知道他是同性恋
And you really didn't know that he was gay?
我该知道的 对吧
I must've, right?